So you know about testing, you know why you should test and
所以，你知道测试，你知道为什么 你应该测试和
you know what to test, but we didn't address yet
你知道要测试什么，但我们还 没有讨论
how to test, how are we going to express to the user of the
如何测试，我们如何向
spreadsheet that a test is broken. Well, there are
电子表格的用户表达测试中出了问题。 那么，有
two different ways that you can test in a given spreadsheet, as you see here.
正如你在这里所看到的， 你可以用两种不同的方式来测试 一个电子表格。
The first thing you can use is conditional formatting.
你可以使用的第一种方式是条件格式化。
Maybe you've used it before - conditional formatting is a feature in Excel
也许你以前已使用过它-条件 格式化是Excel的功能之一，
where you can change the colour or format of a cell
你可以使用它来改变一个单元的颜色或格式
based on specific rules. Here you see how it works.
根据特定的规则。 在这里，你能看到它是如何运作的。
So suppose you want to add conditional formatting on the 'Margin' column.
所以，假设您要在'利润'列里添加条件性的格式。
We select the entire column and then we select
我们选择了整列，然后我们 选择
Conditional Formatting. We get a pop-up screen,
条件格式化 。 我们将得到一个弹出窗口，
and in the screen we can select, there we go,
而在屏幕上，我们可以选择，就这样，
we can select, we want to have a rule for values that are below
我们可以选择，我们要针对低于某门槛的数值
a certain threshold. And then we can say below what threshold should it be,
设定一个规则。 然后，我们可以规定它应该 低于的门槛数值是什么，
and we say if it's below 0 we want to have it become red,
而我们决定若它是低于0，那我们要 把它变成红色，
and then you see it becomes red for all the values below zero.
然后你看将看到所有低于零的数值都会变成红色。
And it immediately works for the entire column because we selected the entire
而这能被运用到整个 列，因为当我们添加次规则时，我们
column when we added the rule. So if we add another
选择了整个列。 所以，如果我们在商业目录里增加 另一
new item to our catalogue and we make a mistake,
新项目，而我们犯了一个 错误，
we immediately get the red value in
我们将立即得到一个红色
the cell. Conditional formatting is nice.
数值。 条件格式化很不错。
It works really well because, as you can see, the erroneous values, they really
它是蛮好用的，因为正如你可以 看到的，错误的数值特别的
hit the eye. They attract your attention because they're really different
显眼。 它们吸引了你的注意力， 因为他们和其他的数值显得
from the other values. However, this is not my preferred way of testing.
不同。 然而，这并不是我 的测试的首选方式。
First of all, some colours can have a different meaning - you can use
首先，有些颜色可以代表 不同的意义 -
conditional formatting, for instance,
例如，
as we do here where, where the red values do not
正如我们在这里所做的， 你可以使用条件格式化 替换红色数值
indicate an error - what they indicate here is
代表的错误 - 他们在这里 代表着
the percentage is below 10 percent. And that just means
该百分比低于10％。 而 这只是意味着
the item isn't selling very well, only less than
该产品的销售量不是很好，这产品只提供了
10 percent of the profit is coming from this item.
少于10％的利润。
So that doesn't mean there's a mistake in my formulas, that means that I
所以，这并不意味在我的公式里有一个错误，这只意味着我
should do a good review of my product catalogue
应该好好审查我的产品的商业目录
to make a decision am I still going to sell this item.
以决定我是否还因该继续销售此产品。
So sometimes,
所以有时候，
the colours red don't indicate wrong values, but they indicate
红色不代表错误 的数值，它们所代表的是
problematic values - a product or an account that just isn't selling so well.
有问题的数值- 一个销量不太好的产品或帐户。
That's one reason why you don't want to use conditional formatting,
这就是为什么你不想要使用条件格式化的原因之一，
and another reason is that if you do it in a different way,
另一个原因是，如果你 以不同的方式来使用它，
as I'm going to show you, you can build formulas on top
正如我现在要示范给你看的，你将能在测试公式里建立其他的
of the test formulas. So let me show you how
公式。 所以，让我告诉你
I prefer to do it. No more conditional formatting, so we're going to clear
我更倾向怎么做。 再没有条件 格式化，所以我们要清除
all the conditional formatting rules and what we're going to do is
所有条件格式化规则，而我们要做的是
add a test formula. So, in another column, we say
添加一个测试公式。 所以，在另一列中， 我们说
"is the margin OK?" and there we add a formula that expresses
“利润没问题吗？” 在那里我们添加了一个公式，表达
what we expect from the values. So we say:
我们从值中所期待的。 所以我们说：
"Hey, if this value is below zero", we say
“嘿，如果该值小于零”，我们会说
"error, this is too low!" and otherwise it's okay.
“错误，这太低了！” 否则 就没关系。
And if we drag the formula down, you see that those erroneous
如果我们向下拖动公式，你看 那些错误
values get a notification "Error, too low!".
值收到通知“错误，太低了！ ”。
And if you do it like this
如果你不喜欢这样
you can build formulas on top of it,
你可以在它上面构建公式，
as I said before. You can use this value because it's just another cell
正如我以前说过的。 你可以使用此值 因为它只是另一个单元格
value, you can use it as the input for another formula.
值，你可以用它作为 另一个公式的输入。
And this might sound a little bit cryptic, so let me show you
这可能听起来有些 模糊，所以让我告诉你
what I exactly mean with that. So what we can do here
我指的究竟是什么。 所以我们这里 能做的是
is add an overall test formula where we're going to check
添加一条整体测试公式，在 我们要检查
is there an error in the list of our
有没有错误
checks. So what we do is we count, we use a COUNTIF,
的检查项列表中。 所以，我们要做的是，计算，我们使用一次COUNTIF，
and we count the number of OKs in
我们计算在整个利润列里面OKs的数量
the whole margin column. And from the number of OKs we subtract
。 而从 OKs的数量里我们减去
the general number, with the COUNTA,
一般数，与 COUNTA，
the number of all items in the list. And now we see
列表中的所有项的数目。 现在我们看到
that this is not 0, it is -2, which means
这不是0，而是-2，这意味着
we don't have the same number of OKs as the total number of values
我们OKs的数量与 我们的数值总数
that we have. That means not everything is OK, so
不一样。 这意味着不正常，
there is an error.
存在错误。
We can add that we don't want -2 as the value, we want again
我们可以补充一点，我们不希望-2是数值，我们希望再次
to make this into a test formula, so we say: if it's -2
把这个放入测试公式，所以 我们说：如果它是-2
then it's an error. If it's any value below 0,
那么有错误。 如果它的任何值 低于0，
then there's an error and otherwise
那么就是有错误，否则，
it's OK. So now we've build a test formula on
没关系。 所以，现在我们已经在已有测试公式上
top of all the test formulas that we already had. And we can repeat this
建立了一个测试公式。 我们可以重复这个
process,
过程，
we can add a number of columns next to it, and say for all of the columns
我们可以在旁边添加一些列， 对所有列
add another test formula. And we can repeat this trick
添加另一个测试公式。 我们可以 在较高级别上
at the higher level where those four column tests,
重复这一招，这四 列进行测试，
again we're going to combine them into one test
我们再次将它们组合成 一个测试
where we count the number of OKs, and the number of OKs
在这里我们计数OKs的数量， OKS的数量
should be equal to the number
应等于
of items, test cells in our list.
我们测试列表里面的项目数。
So now we can have one big test at the end of the
所以，现在我们在工作表末有一个很大的测试
worksheet, where all the test columns and all the overall tests come together.
，其中所有的测试列和 所有的整体测试整合到一起。
And then this is a formula again where we want to add conditional formatting,
然后这又是一个公式，公式中我们 想要添加条件格式化 ，
because in this error there's no way this can mean anything else. If a cell that says
因为这个错误中绝不可能指其他含义。 如果一个单元格写着
Error is red,
错误是红色的，
probably something is up there. There's no other meaning that this could have. So for such a
大概是有什么东西在那里。 这不可能有其他含义。 因此，对于这样的
final test formula, adding conditional formatting
最后的测试公式，加入条件 格式化
is a really good idea!
是一个非常不错的主意！